WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
I don't know why you always
wait for me. There's no need.
I want to be the first
to greet you every morning.
Well, as I said...there's no need.
There's -
There's every need.
And I will keep it up until you
explain to me what has gone wrong
between us. Explain what?
My life is perfect.
And then, in the space of one day,
it is nothing.
To me, that requires an explanation.
Oh, good morning, Miss Baxter.
Hello, Mr Bates, Mrs Bates.
I wondered if you'd help me.
We will, if we can.
It's my sewing machine.
I have no sockets in my room.
And, as the sewing room
is in the laundry wing,
I wondered if Mrs Hughes might let
me use it in the servants' hall.
I should ask her, if I were you.
Yes, of course.
I'll do that.
What do you make of her?
I think she's nice. Which prompts me to
wonder what she sees in our friend Thomas.
You know the old saying.
'There's nowt so queer as folk.'
We'll miss breakfast,
if we're not careful.
Are you happy for us to be
teaching Alfred to cook?
It's Mr Carson you should ask.
Ask me what?
About the kitchen staff
helping Alfred to train for his test.
He's been accepted for it, then?
Not yet, no.
But he'd like to be ready if he is.
I suppose it's all right.
Alfred is a hard worker.
I'll give him that.
And if cooking's his chosen path...
Good. I was just checking
I wasn't inciting a revolution.
There we are...My Lady.
I think I've remembered everything.
But...
I'll just stay here while you check.
It seems perfect, but...
What's this?
Well, I know Americans often
drink orange juice with breakfast.
So I thought you might like it.
That is so considerate, Baxter.
Thank you.
Good morning, My Lord.
Good morning.
You look very jovial.
It's just Baxter reminding me
of times gone by.
You're pleased with her.
I am, thank heaven.
What's your day looking like?
Tom and Mary have summoned me
to the library.
They have an idea.
I hope it's not something
you're going to fight about.
How can I answer that
when I don't know what it is.
So if we find a job for the boy,
it'll make a difference
to his mother.
Oh, a big difference. If you really
want to help Mrs Pegg,
this will be of more use than
a world of tea and sympathy.
Well, I don't need anyone else here.
I know.
But would you talk to
the head gardener up at the abbey?
Or maybe even talk to Lady Grantham.
She takes her garden seriously.
You don't have to tell me that.
I'm sorry. When's the funeral?
Tomorrow. Will you go?
I will. His forebears have been
tenants since the reign
of George III.
Be that as it may,
the rent's not been paid for ages.
We've served all the papers.
It's time to get on with it.
You mean, foreclose the lease
and farm the land ourselves?
That's what we discussed.
It's sad, though.
After such a long time
in the hands of one family.
The world moves on,
and we must move with it.
So you keep telling me.
Talking of the world moving on,
I suppose you've seen this.
'The engagement is announced between
the Viscount Gillingham
and the Honourable Mabel Lane Fox,
only child of the late
Lord Osweston.'
Well, I must...
write and congratulate him.
Now...let me get on.
But it's electric. Aren't you
worried it'll run away with itself
and sew your fingers to the table?
I certainly hope not.
How do you operate it?
With a pedal - under my foot.
Well, I don't think it has
any business in a servants' hall.
But there's no socket in her room.
She could take it to the laundry.
Or, better still,
chuck it out altogether!
Mrs Patmore is not
what you'd call a futurist (!)
I think I'd got there already (!)
Anna.
I've forgotten something.
You must forgive me, Mr Bates.
I'm afraid I'm keeping Anna too busy.
Would you like to have a try?
Anna?
I don't know why you must be
so hard on Mr Bates.
At least you know now there'll be...
no baby.
No.
Then, can't you start
to get past it and...
and tell him something?
He'd know if it wasn't the truth.
He sees through me.
He can read me like a book.
I wish he could read you.
And take you out of this...
veil of shadows.
Don't you want to be honest with him?
Of course I do.
But I know him. I know what he'd do.
And I can't risk his future.
Well...it's your secret and not mine.
But I think it's a mistake.
And you're sure
you have a feel for gardening?
I am, Your Ladyship. I'm not
a ladyship. Just Mrs Crawley.
I...I don't know much now.
But I'm a grafter.
And a quick learner.
I cannot make promises, but I will
try and find something for you.
Thank you very much, Your Ladyship.
Will you show him out?
He's going to be so disappointed
when he finds out how ordinary
I really am.
You're part of the family.
That's how the village sees you.
It's not how the family see me.
Oh, I'm not so sure about that.
Lord and Lady Grantham have always
been as kind as they can be.
And I appreciate it. But I am not one
of them. And that's the end of it.
Lord Grantham admires you very much.
But if it serves you to think
yourself unloved, nothing I
say will change that.
I think that's rather harsh.
Lord Grantham.
It was a very good service.
Your father would've been pleased.
Thank you.
Do you have far to go?
I'm staying at Yew Tree Farm.
Of course.
Let us know when you're
ready to leave. There's no hurry.
The thing is, My Lord,
I...don't want to move out.
I want to take on the tenancy.
What?
If it's still possible.
I'm sorry to be the one to say it,
but I don't believe it is.
The notices have been served.
The case is closed.
You mean,
you want to farm the land yourself.
Then it's all settled.
Mr Drewe, it's no good
painting me as Simon Legree.
We gave your father a long time
to get straight.
And left him in peace
at the end of his life.
He never told me about the debt.
Or I'd've tried to help him.
Because my ancestors have farmed at
Yew Tree since the Napoleonic Wars.
Surely, that's got to mean something.
It means a great deal to me.
Then, can we talk about it, My Lord?
Please?
Come tomorrow morning, if you wish.
But I can't see
what good it will do.
Don't take it off too soon.
Let it bubble a bit,
or you'll taste the flour.
So...is this enough?
I'd say so, yeah.
Now put it to one side
while you check your casings.
My, my. Something smells good.
Alfred's making tarts with
an egg and cheese filling. Oh.
Bouchees de fromage.
They could be tonight's savoury.
Do you think? I don't see why not.
I'll fetch the eggs.
Well done, Daisy.
It's very hard, Mrs Patmore.
I feel like I'm helping him
to leave us. And so you are.
Which is as it should be,
now he's decided to go.
So, what's next? We'll add
egg and cheese to the white sauce,
if Mrs Patmore doesn't mind.
I don't mind at all, Daisy. You can
help him enrich the bechamel.
Your Ladyship. My Lady.
Is that the afternoon post?
Is there anything for me?
There's just a couple
for His Lordship, My Lady.
Were you expecting something?
Not particularly.
I haven't heard from Michael
in a bit, that's all.
I expect he's busy.
What have you been up to?
I was writing to Tony Gillingham.
Give him my regards.
Say we look forward to knowing
Miss Lane Fox.
I am surprised.
I thought he was rather keen on you.
Not for the first time, you've
got the wrong end of the stick.
Oh. I thought you were Robert.
Is he back from his funeral?
Not yet, I don't think.
While he's not here,
shall we discuss his birthday?
Oh, does he have a birthday soon?
Fairly soon.
Do you have any plans?
Nothing beyond his favourite food.
It's not a special one.
Why don't we have a party?
To cheer ourselves up. A small one.
That'll be fun.
But Maley may have a candidate
of his own that he wants
to bring forward.
So, you do need extra help.
I suppose so.
The last boy went off
to a frightfully grand rectory.
Then, will you take young Pegg?
He impressed me so favourably.
You know, I wonder your halo
doesn't grow heavy.
It must be like wearing a tiara
round the clock.
Will you help him?
His mother would be very grateful.
And so would I. Yes, but
your gratitude never seems to last.
I've no sooner said yes than
you come back with another request.
Will you?
Very well. Very well.
But he'd better turn out
to be all the things you say he is.
Thought I'd get an extra
10 minutes in before the gong goes.
You can help me with this.
Sybbie says there's going to be
a hurricane any moment now.
A hurricane? Really? In Yorkshire?
So we're getting all the animals
under shelter.
I'm sure you are. Where's Nanny?
Collecting some clothes
from laundry.
I said I'd stay with them.
She's so much more relaxed
than our nanny ever was.
My childhood wasn't
anything like Sybbie's.
Nor mine, God knows. Do you think
she's having a good childhood?
That we're doing well? I think
you're doing your best for her...
if that's what you mean.
It isn't quite.
Oh. I think it's time
for the hurricane.
Whoo!
Uh-oh. Uh-oh.
This came for you in the last post.
Is that the letter that says if
they'll see you? I think it must be.
Well, open it, then. Oh, go on.
Don't keep us in suspense.
I want it so much. I can't bear
to find out I've not got it.
Give it to me, then.
Well, they are going to test you.
Oh, they are.
But, by 'eck.
It's the day after tomorrow.
They don't give you much time.
Oh, this was posted 10 days ago.
It must've got lost.
He'll be fine.
He knows his stuff.
Course he does. Doesn't he, Daisy?
He does, yeah.
What's this?
Alfred's got his test. At The Ritz.
I'm happy for you, Alfred.
Anna...
That's the gong.
I shouldn't worry, Mr Bates.
She's got ever so much on her plate.
Haven't we all?
Oh, bravo!
Very good!
She's right.
I couldn't have done better myself.
Now. Take them up
and say you cooked 'em.
I couldn't.
Well, Mr Carson can say it.
And what are they supposed to do?
Hang out the flags?
Oh, don't grudge him his success.
I don't.
I just can't see the fun
in a life chained to a stove.
Are the savouries ready to go up?
They certainly are.
I say. Well done.
We'll be sorry to lose you, Alfred.
But I think you'll pass your test.
Fingers crossed, My Lady.
When is it? The day after tomorrow.
I'm going up in the morning.
Our best wishes go with you.
I'm going up myself tomorrow.
Oh?
Just for the day.
To visit Michael's office.
I'll be back for dinner.
All alone?
I seem to be.
I don't know why.
How are you getting on with
Her Ladyship?
Pretty well...I think.
You've done America and
praised Lady Sybil? Have I not (!)
You name it, I've said it.
She'll be eating out of your hand.
That's the intention.
No enemies downstairs neither.
That was Miss O'Brien's mistake.
Nobody liked her,
so nobody told her anything.
They don't like you much.
That's why you're here.
To rectify that failing on my part.
Is it true you've moved
into the house again?
Mrs Hughes said so.
It seemed easier when I was looking
after Her Ladyship as well as you.
But she has her own maid now.
Why not go back to the cottage?
I haven't got round to it.
Anna, if you're in difficulties,
I wish you'd tell me.
I'm not, My Lady. Honestly.
I've come to say goodbye.
Thank you for all your help.
Just keep calm. You know enough
to do well if you keep calm.
Very good luck, Alfred.
Is there anything I ought to
know about London?
There's quite a lot you ought to
know about London, dear.
And no time to tell it now
or he'll miss his train.
This afternoon,
when Her Ladyship comes down,
I don't want any backchat -
she must see everything is in order,
all neat and tidy.
What's happened to your apron?
Why? What should -
Oh, my God!
What's up?
Well...I must've
caught it on a nail.
My other's in the wash.
And Her Ladyship's due!
Oh, don't worry. Miss Baxter'll
sort that out. Give it here. Right.
I thought you wouldn't mind if
Alfred rode in the front, My Lady.
He's catching the same train.
Of course I don't mind.
We all wish you luck, Alfred.
I'm going to need it, My Lady.
It's his first trip to London.
How exciting.
Exciting's one word for it.
You want to reverse the foreclosure
and take the lease,
but you still can't pay
all the arrears.
It doesn't seem
a very enticing offer.
I'll pay. And it won't take long.
Even so...
I'm a Yorkshireman, My Lord.
This is where I belong.
We've worked this land
in partnership with the Crawleys
for more than a century.
In partnership with the Crawleys?
I don't mean to be impertinent.
I do not hear it as impertinence.
We have been in partnership.
We're in partnership with
all our tenants. Or, we should be.
Then, will you let me come home?
I'll see what I can do.
Thank you, My Lord.
I'll be at the farm.
Mr Drewe.
I would prefer to report that you
are prepared to repay the
arrears in full.
I'll lend you the difference myself.
You'd do that for me?
It won't be less than £50.
I'll send a cheque
when I'm sure of the outcome.
You won't regret it.
No.
I don't think I will.
Do you think Alfred has a chance
with his cooking?
I think he's got more than a chance,
judging by what Mrs Patmore
has to say on the subject.
Because I've got an idea that might
kill two birds with one stone.
We'll be short of a footman any day
and Mr Molesley will be
short of a job.
What say we deal with
the two problems together?
And solve both.
Exactly.
- But would he do it?
- Would he do it (?)
When he's been mending roads
and delivering groceries,
and lucky to get even that?
I'll say he'll do it.
I hope you're right.
I know I am.
You might've talked it over with us
before you made up your mind.
But I haven't. I told him
we'd think about it. That's all.
Sounds to me as if
you've come to a decision.
If we don't respect the past,
it'll be harder to build our future.
Where did you read that?
I made it up.
I thought it was rather good.
It's too good.
One thing we don't want
is a poet in the family (!)
Would it be so bad?
The only poet peer
I am familiar with is Lord Byron.
And I presume you all know
how that ended.
So, you'd let Mr Drewe stay on.
Since he wants to repay the debt,
I think it only fair.
Besides, he talks of the partnership
between the farmers and the family,
and I like that.
Well, I think it's splendid.
Says the queen of the rebels (!)
Thank you. And you agree, even though
he has no right to renew the lease?
No right legally, no.
But we think he has a moral right.
It's a pity it should be Yew Tree.
It would've filled a hole in
the land we farm.
You've managed without it till now.
You haven't said what you think.
Which side are you on?
The farmer's, of course.
I've not abandoned all my socialism.
Even though it feels like it
sometimes.
In this one and only instance,
I am glad to hear it.
When will you tell him?
There's no tearing rush.
We've a day or two to talk it over.
And then you can tell him.
It's strange...standing here
next to you in silence.
Because I love you.
I want to find out
why you don't love me any more.
You'd think we could talk about it.
But apparently not.
But I don't...
I'm going into Ripon this afternoon
to get some things for Lady Mary.
If they miss me,
I'll be back before the gong.
Well...
At least I know you'll be back
before the gong (!)
Ooh! I can't get over
the speed of it.
I feel quite dizzy watching.
I don't think it'll show.
Show? It's better than it was
before I bought it.
Aw! Thanks very much.
Her Ladyship's on her way down.
Another one roped to the chariot (!)
I'm grateful for this job, Thomas.
And we both know why.
But what's it all about?
Well, there's going to be changes
at Downton. There's bound to be.
I'm sure.
So I want to know about
any plans upstairs.
Any detail, no matter how small.
Understand?
Did the other lady's maids
keep you informed?
Miss O'Brien, yes. But we fell out.
What about Mrs Bates?
Is she an enemy?
She knows what's going on.
No, she's not an enemy.
But she's incorruptible.
So we have nothing in common.
She's also silent.
Shouldn't think I've had four words
out of her since I arrived.
Just get them all to trust you...
and tell you everything.
Your Ladyship. How can I help?
I've come down to persuade you.
I just don't see why it's
better than an ice box.
Well, a refrigerator
is more efficient.
It keeps food fresh longer.
We won't need ice to be delivered.
But the papers will still
be delivered, and the groceries,
and all sorts.
Or are we to stop that too?
Mrs Patmore.
Is there any aspect of the present
day that you can accept without
resistance?
Well, My Lady.
(I wouldn't mind
getting rid of my corset.)
You must do everything
Maley tells you.
I will, Your Ladyship.
John is keen to learn. Aren't you?
I am, ma'am. Because there's
always work for a good gardener.
You owe your place to Mrs Crawley.
She would not let me go until
I'd promised.
She would not relax her grip.
You make me sound very fervent.
Wars have been waged with
less fervour (!)
Well, let's hope we win this one.
Good day, John.
Say what you like, but I know
you care about these things
as much as I do.
Nobody cares about
anything as much as you do.
This is it.
My name is Arsene Avignon.
I am the sous chef of The Ritz.
Today...you are going to make
four dishes.
Is that clear? Then, if you have
no questions, we will begin.
In 1917,
at our sister hotel in New York,
the chef, Monsieur Diat,
altered a soup made popular
by Monsieur Gouffe and...
the great Monsieur Escoffier.
What did he do?
He served it cold.
Very good. Yes, it was eaten cold.
Previously,
the name had been a simple one.
Leek and potato soup. But...
what was it called now?
Vichyssoise.
It was Vichyssoise.
So...you all have
the instructions before you.
Please begin.
Mr Napier.
What?
Hello, Mary.
I can still call you Mary?
Of course you can. How lovely.
What brings you here?
I'm working on a government thing
and we've got some research
to do in Yorkshire.
I'm on a sort of...
reconnoitring expedition.
Lucky me.
I was in Thirsk, and I suddenly
thought, why not take a chance?
Well, I'm so glad you did.
Let me give you some tea.
I'll get them to tell Mama and Papa
that you're here.
While I've got you alone...
You've been in my thoughts
a great deal...
since the whole...ghastly business.
That's nice to know.
Which is why it's lovely to
see you looking so um...
..lovely.
Hello. Lady Mary wants tea for four.
I'll...start again? Hello? Lady Mary
wants tea for four in the library?
It's not right, you know,
when you speak against Alfred.
Sorry. But imagine having
never been to London.
Dearie me.
I've not been to London.
And, for me, it just goes to show.
He may be nervous,
it may be a daunting prospect,
but he's got ambition.
It drives him. And I admire that.
Good.
Because I've got plenty of ambition
where you're concerned.
Don't be so soft.
So...what is this thing
you're working on?
It's all to do with
the rural economy. Very hush-hush.
Well, don't tell us if it's
meant to be a secret.
Well, it's...not like that.
A lot of landed estates
are in difficulty.
The department wants to assess
the damage of the war years.
Are they likely to survive,
and so on. And are they?
Some of them.
It sounds rather interesting.
It is. Interesting
and incredibly depressing.
Which places are you studying
in Yorkshire?
That I cannot say.
It wouldn't be fair on the owners.
But we have earmarked the ones
in serious trouble.
And you'll be glad to know
Downton's not among them.
Still, we'd love your opinion on
whether or not we're doing the right
things. Wouldn't we, Papa?
We don't want to add to his labours.
Where are you staying
while you're up here?
We haven't decided.
There's quite a good hotel in Ripon.
Nonsense. You must stay with us.
I couldn't possibly.
Why not?
Well, to start with, I'll have
my boss with me. Who's that?
Charles Blake.
Have you ever come across him?
I don't think so.
You must both stay here.
That way, we'll get the benefit
of all your knowledge
for the price of a couple of dinners.
What could be better than that?
Well, Mr Nugent.
You've done...quite well.
I know I can do better, sir,
if you give me a chance. I know it.
You haven't chosen to make your
living in the kitchen before now.
No. You see, my mother was keen -
You have worked instead as a footman
for the Earl of Grantham.
I have, yes.
And this has made you...unhappy?
I'll not say that.
But I want to do more with my life.
I see. Well,
we have difficult decisions ahead.
But don't worry.
We won't keep you waiting.
It's good of you...to let me
disturb your afternoon.
You see...
I have to get to the bottom
of what's troubling me.
And I believe you can help.
I doubt that.
The thing is...I know you can.
I heard you questioning Anna about
why she was being so hard on me.
But that doesn't mean -
Yes. It does.
You know what this is about.
And you believe...
she should have told me.
Well, I admit...
I think she should have.
But it is not for me to.
Then I can't stay here.
What?
I have been happy in this house.
Happier than I had any right to be.
But that only makes my present
situation all the harder to bear.
I can imagine.
Can you?
Can you, Mrs Hughes?
Because if you can...
..you will know why
I have to leave here.
My wife no longer loves me.
The sight of me is torture for her,
which is torture for me.
If you will not let me
hear the truth...
I will hand in my resignation now
and be gone before she gets back.
So be it.
Wait!
Where is Anna?
She...had an errand in Ripon.
It's not true.
Anna loves you very, very much.
And I think the pain of coming home
to find you gone would finish her.
So I will tell you what happened...
to make you stay.
And if I'm doing the wrong thing,
then I ask for the mercy of God.
I'm sorry, My Lady. They said you
wouldn't be in here before seven.
No. Nor would I be.
But I left a...letter on my desk.
Has anybody else -
Oh.
Has anybody else been in here?
I don't know, Your Ladyship.
No.
No, why would you?
That's all of it.
You haven't said when...it happened.
Haven't I?
Was it the last night
of the houseparty?
When she told me...
she fainted...and hit her head.
Is that when it happened?
Yes.
Then I know who it really was.
I've told you who it was.
But I don't believe you!
I think it was Lord Gillingham's
valet, who teased her
and flirted with her
from the moment he arrived.
It was not Lord Gillingham's valet.
I don't believe he ever
left the concert. It was not him.
Do you swear that?
Why should I swear?
You must swear it -
on everything you hold dear!
Will you?
I've said...
It was an outsider. It was no-one
who was staying in the house.
A man broke in and waited down here.
How many times must I repeat it?
Do you swear?
Very well. If it makes you
feel better, I swear.
On your mother's life?
She is dead. On her grave.
I've said I swear!
Because I will find out who he is.
You're welcome to try.
But I don't know
what you've got to go on.
Ah, there you are.
How did you get on?
Oh, fine.
I hear Evelyn Napier
was here earlier.
I'm sorry to have missed him.
Yes, he just dropped in.
It was a spur of the moment thing.
Is he still in pursuit of Mary?
I didn't ask him.
So, will you be giving
a birthday party? For Robert?
Why? Do you really want me to?
I'd had rather a good idea for it.
That's all.
If I did, would you give me a hand?
Absolutely. Shh!
So. Have we come to
a final decision about Drewe?
I suppose so.
If it means that much to you.
And Tom's socialism will ensure
his approval of the plan.
You laugh. But, as a matter
of fact, I've been thinking about
it quite a lot lately.
About what?
My beliefs, I suppose. I'm not
too sure what they are any more.
Since the houseparty - I won't hear
another word about the houseparty.
Somebody said something
to upset you. That's all it is.
What was this? Who was rude?
No-one. He's got that wrong.
I just...felt like an intruder.
It made me face the fact that
I'm living where I don't belong.
Welcome to the club (!)
Oh, stop moaning.
But, if you went back to Ireland,
Tom, would you belong there?
No. I don't think I would.
You've changed me too much.
I'm a man without a home.
I am stateless.
Well, then...
There is America.
I have family there
and they're doing quite well.
It would be a new start.
But you've made a new start here.
But I'm talking about
the world Sybbie will grow up in.
Wouldn't it be easier for her
to begin with a clean slate,
rather than being the daughter of
an uppity chauffeur?
Well, don't do anything in a hurry.
We don't want to lose you, Tom.
What do you mean,
you'll have to think about it?
What I say. I didn't mind helping
you out when you were short-staffed.
How good of you (!) But to accept a
permanent position as a footman...
I'm a trained valet, Mr Car-
I'm a trained butler!
To accept...my fall by taking
a permanent, inferior place...
You keep telling me it's permanent.
But from where I'm sitting, it's
looking less permanent by the minute!
I shall give it every consideration.
Very generous, I must say (!)
I'll let you know my answer
when I have one.
I shall wait with bated breath (!)
Aren't you ever
going to finish that?
It's nearly midnight.
Someone has to do it. But it
doesn't always have to be you.
I know.
I know what happened.
Mrs Hughes told me. I forced her to.
Then, she was very wrong.
It wasn't her secret to tell.
I gave her no choice, Anna.
What did she say?
How...
How it happened.
When it happened.
I asked if it was Green.
Who?
Mr Green.
Lord Gillingham's valet.
She swore it wasn't.
No, it wasn't him.
She said a man...
..broke in and was waiting
down here for you, a stranger.
That's right.
Because, if it was the valet...
..he is a dead man.
It wasn't him! You only say that
because you didn't like him.
No, I did not.
There's no excuse to accuse him
when he did nothing.
Would I have sat at breakfast with
him next morning if it'd been him?
We can't know who the man was.
We have no way of tracing him.
Why wouldn't you tell me?
Because I knew the suffering
it would bring you.
Well, it's in the open.
No more secrets.
I'm glad of that, at least.
No more fear of being found out.
Because I am found out.
My shame has nowhere to hide.
Why do you talk of shame?
I don't accept that
there is any shame in this.
But I am spoiled for you.
And I can never be unspoiled.
You are not spoiled.
You are made...
higher to me...
and holier because of the suffering
you have been put through.
You are my wife.
And I have never been prouder...
..nor loved you more
than I love you now at this moment.
Truly?
Truly.
Morning.
Alfred.
Is that the result?
I think so, yes.
Do you want me to open it?
No, I'll do it myself.
Good luck.
Well?
I've not got it.
What?
Oh, I am sorry.
It says I did well and I was nearly
in the top four, but not quite.
I expect they say that to everyone.
That's enough, James.
And Alfred - to fail at the first
attempt does not mean that you
won't succeed later.
Quite right.
Might I have a word, Mr Carson?
Certainly.
I've given it a lot of thought.
Have you, indeed (?)
First,
I needed to deal with
my father's disappointment,
when he learned of my downward path.
But I weighed it against the power
to do good that all employment
brings.
Did you, now?
And you thought all that.
I feel I could contain my skills
and guide them
into a...more modest channel
without loss of dignity.
Just fancy (!)
So, all in all...
and after mature deliberation,
you'll be pleased to hear that
I can accept your offer.
What offer?
To replace Alfred as footman.
Oh, dear, Mr Molesley. I'm afraid
that Alfred's not leaving now.
It's a pity you didn't
accept the job when we last talked.
And then I'd have been
stuck with you.
As it is, you've missed your chance.
As I generally do.
Mature deliberation (!)
Cheer up, lad.
You read the letter.
You were a very near miss. So,
next time, you'll hit the target.
I reckon Jimmy's right.
They say that to everyone who fails.
Well, I reckon you work hard
and you deserve to succeed.
You just have to stick at it...
and you will.
I'm not saying he took it.
But I don't see
who else could've done.
In other words,
you're saying he took it.
I know he was in this room.
Legitimately.
Really, Dr Clarkson. I'm not
a witness for the prosecution.
Aren't you?
Well, let us review the facts.
I have lost a valuable paper knife.
Given to the late Lord Grantham
by the King of Sweden.
Which makes all the difference (!)
It makes the loss greater, yes.
I quite agree.
But I can't accept there's any
real proof against erm...young Pegg.
Well, if you insist,
I won't sack him. Yet.
But I will not allow him
back in the house.
And I will have to speak
to my head gardener about it.
That will do him a lot of harm.
Well, what would you prefer?
That I invite the local criminals
to drop in and strip the house bare?
Why not ask to be told
when a gardener is coming inside?
So that you or a servant
can keep watch.
Then we'll have time to investigate
the loss of the knife.
Or have you already scented blood?
As a matter of interest,
do you ever doubt?
I don't doubt the honesty
of young Pegg.
That is not at all what I asked.
I'm very grateful, My Lady.
You didn't have to do this,
but it determines me to prove
I'm worthy of your faith.
I can't pretend to take the credit,
Mr Drewe.
It was His Lordship
who was determined you should stay.
You owe your thanks to him.
He'll have my thanks, My Lady.
And he'll have the rest of
the payment before he's missed it.
What payment?
Remainder of the debt.
I thought you'd know about it.
And so we do.
Of course we do. I'm sorry.
I was being absent-minded.
How much is it? I've forgotten.
It's only the last £50.
He sent a cheque so I can pay off
the full amount and wipe
the slate clean.
Well, thank you, Mr Drewe.
I'm sure we have many fruitful
years ahead of us.
Are you going to challenge him?
No. If Papa believes enough in Drewe
to lend him the money,
and to hide it from us,
then that tells me something.
What, exactly? That you and I are in
partnership with a very decent man.
Mrs Hughes, can I have a word?
I know you told Mr Bates about me
while I was out yesterday.
He put me in a very...difficult...
I'm afraid he guessed who it was.
But you denied it.
Denied it?
I swore on my mother's grave
it wasn't him...God help me.
He seems to have accepted your word.
In fact...
I'm moving back into the cottage.
Oh! Oh, I'm...I'm so pleased.
At least if I'm damned for all
eternity, it was to some purpose.
You won't be damned.
Mr Bates has shown
great generosity of spirit.
As I knew he would. Eventually.
So...we're going to try and put
the whole thing behind us.
I hate to think of that evil man
getting away scot free.
But maybe it's for the best.
I thought you'd like to know.
What are you grinning about?
What do you think? He's not going.
Mr Bates. I'm so glad to see you.
Anna's told me
what's gone on between you.
And it's made me
happier than I can say.
To think it's all
over and done with.
Nothing's over and done with,
Mrs Hughes.
But Anna said -
Do you think I would add to her
burden, after all she's been through?
I don't know his name,
so I can't tell it to you.
Not if you were to threaten me
with a knife, Mr Bates.
I understand. And I won't press you.
But be aware.
Nothing is over.
And nothing is done with.
Michael's vanished into thin air.
If anything had happened, we'd know.
I was a fool to think
we could leave it behind.
I'm the failure here, not you.
Can I interrupt?
Mr Napier and Mr Blake
are here in a few days.
You're here to advise the landowners
on how to get through this crisis,
aren't you? Not quite.
You seem to have brought
a traitor into our midst.
Not a traitor.
I wonder you don't just set fire
to the abbey and dance round it.
Painted with woad and howling (!)
I might. If it would do any good.
This came in the evening post.
Is anything the matter?